(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みんなー！ ORIOです！
Everyone! We are ORIO!
Over Time
作詞：やぎぬまかな
作曲・編曲：佐藤カズキ
Over Time
Lyrics: Kana Yaginuma
Composition/Arrangement: Kazuki Sato
今日が初ライブ！
Today is our first live!
その目にしっかり焼き付けてねー！
Make sure to burn this into your eyes!
些細な事　逆らって
Resisting even the trivial things
いつの間にか　痛みだしていた
Before I knew it, it started to hurt
一人じゃないって　分かってるけど
I know I'm not alone, but
どうしても孤独に呑まれそう
I feel like I'm being swallowed by loneliness anyway
同じ場所で躓いても
Even if I stumble in the same place
少しずつ進んでいければいいから
It's okay as long as I can move forward little by little
触れられなくてもここには
Even if I can't touch it, right here
確かな光あるんだ
There is a certain light
ボクらは　散るまでずっとサバイバー
We are survivors until the very end
道なき道を往く
Going down a pathless road
誰もが　迷える子羊なんだ
Everyone is a lost lamb
聞かせて　小さなことも
Tell me, even the little things
ah　完璧じゃなくても
Ah, even if it's not perfect
前を向いたのならきっと繋がっていく
If you look forward, it will surely connect
終わりのない闇の中で
In the endless darkness
俯いては溢れ出す溜息
A sigh that overflows when I look down
出口のないことばかりを
With nothing but things with no exit
考えてまた繰り返して
I think about them again and again
うまく伝えられなくても
Even if I can't convey it well
言葉を重ねてみたいんだよ
I want to try layering words
踏み出す一歩怖くても
Even if taking the first step is scary
その先の景色見たいんだ
I want to see the scenery beyond that
天使と悪魔がついてるから
Because an angel and a devil are with you
いつでも
Anytime,
すぐそばに
Right by your side.
荒波だらけの
A battlefield full of rough waves
戦場がなんだ
Is no problem for us.
ボクらはきっと大丈夫
We'll surely be alright.
ah 痛みの分だけ
Ah, just as much as the pain,
強くなれてるんだ、ってさ
We're growing stronger, they say,
信じてる
And I believe it.
知らずに「普通」の檻に
Without knowing, in the cage of 'normality',
囚われていた無意識を
The unconsciousness that was imprisoned...
そっと解放してみよう さぁ
Let's gently release it, come on.
ボクらは散るまでずっと
We are survivors
サバイバー
Until the moment we fall.
道なき道を往く
Treading on a pathless path,
誰もが迷える子羊なんだ
Everyone is just a lost lamb.
聞かせて 小さなことも
Let me hear it, even the smallest things.
ah 完璧じゃなくても
Ah, even if it's not perfect,
前を向けたのならきっと
If you can look forward, surely,
繋がっていく
We'll stay connected.
諦めない そう決めたの
I won't give up, that's what I decided.
赤き心を燃やして
Burning my crimson heart.
正解か 不正解かは
Whether it's right or wrong,
どうだっていいんだってさ
They say it doesn't matter.
走り抜けた足跡 そのまま
The footprints of our sprint, just as they are,
物語になっていく
Will become a story.
擦りむいた 瘡蓋なぞって
Tracing the scabs of our grazes,
痛みをチカラに変えていくんだ
We'll turn the pain into strength.
何度も 翼広げて
Spreading our wings again and again,
ここに刻む この鼓動が真実のsign
This heartbeat etched here is a sign of truth.
限界だって
Blowing away even our limits,
吹き飛ばして
We'll keep going.
燃えて燃えて燃え尽きても また甦る
Even if we burn and burn out, we'll revive again.
決して諦めたくはないから
Because I never want to give up.
Like a Phoenix
揺れて 躓いても
Even if we waver and stumble,
消えない 燈火
The light will not go out.
心駆り立てるから
It stirs my heart,
幾度も 灰になっても構わない
I don't mind turning to ash many times.
見上げれば 高すぎる空
Looking up, the sky is so high,
眩暈がしても 止められないんだ
Even if I feel dizzy, I can't be stopped.
感情を 滾らせながら
Letting my emotions boil over,
光求め もがいている 本能のscream
Seeking light, struggling, an instinctive scream.
停滞なんて
Smashing through any stagnation,
ぶち壊して
We'll keep going.
息を切らし 不器用でも たどり着くから
Out of breath, clumsy as we are, we'll reach it.
最短距離で駆け抜けたいんだ
I want to sprint through the shortest distance.
Like a Phoenix
声を枯らしてもまだ
Even if my voice goes hoarse, still,
届けたい熱が冷めなくて
The heat I want to deliver won't cool down.
溢れてく 思いの分だけ
Overflowing, as much as our feelings,
決意を速度に変えて
Turning our determination into speed.
Change your determination into speed
higher!
何度も翼広げて
Spreading my wings many times
ここに刻む鼓動だけが真実のsign
Only the heartbeat carved here is the sign of truth
限界だって
Even if it's the limit
吹き飛ばしてく
I'll blow it away
燃えて 燃えて 燃え尽きてもまた蘇る
Burning, burning, even if I burn out, I will rise again
決して諦めたくはないから
Because I never want to give up
Like a Phoenix
Speak up about your unspoken prayer
We are the one that rescues you right now
We are the one that rescues you all
禁じ手だらけの人生
A life full of forbidden moves
演じてたはずの理想像
The ideal image I was supposed to be performing
今日だけは全て解き放って
Just for today, release everything
見て 信じてみるのもいいね
Look, it's okay to try believing
決して忘れることのない
That I will never forget
音を聞かせるから
Because I'll let you hear the sound
Here we are to save you
Just wake up Here we are to save you
その手 伸ばし 祈れ
Reach out your hand and pray
歌うなら show me what you got
If you're going to sing, show me what you got
冷えたなら I'm so tired
If you've cooled down, I'm so tired
従うなら I'm gonna give you chances
If you're going to obey, I'm gonna give you chances
Let me take you
To the hell もしくは to the heaven
To the hell or to the heaven
歌えるなら make a sound right here
If you can sing, make a sound right here
他には何にもいらない そうでしょ？
You don't need anything else, right?
Speak up about your unspoken prayer
We are the one that rescues you right now
Be the one
Speak up about your unspoken prayer We are the one that rescues you right now
Here we are
Speak up about your unspoken prayer We are the one that rescues you all
Be the one
Just wake up Here we are to save you
行こうか Just wake up Here we are to save you
Let's go, Just wake up Here we are to save you
その手 伸ばし 祈れ
Reach out your hand and pray
Are you ready?
禁じ手だらけの人生
A life full of forbidden moves
演じてたはずの理想像
The ideal image I was supposed to be performing
今日からは全て打ち壊して
From today, smash everything
信じていたいのなら
If you want to believe
決して忘れることのない
That I will never forget
音を鳴らしてよ
Let the sound ring out
歌うなら show me what you got
If you're going to sing, show me what you got
冷えたなら I'm so tired
If you've cooled down, I'm so tired
従うなら I'm gonna give you chances
If you're going to obey, I'm gonna give you chances
Let me take you
To the hell もしくは to the heaven
To the hell or to the heaven
歌えるなら make a sound right here
If you can sing, make a sound right here
他には何にもいらない そうでしょ？
You don't need anything else, right?
歌えさわげ 宴は続く
Sing and make a racket, the feast continues
舞え おにけもだんす
Dance, the Onikemo Dance
はっ！
Ha!
ヤヤヤヤヤ
Ya ya ya ya ya
コンコンコンコン
Kon kon kon kon
みょんみょんみょんみょん
Myaon myaon myaon myaon
オニキツネイヌ 神社！
Oni Kitsune Inu Shrine!
一二三で七変化
One, two, three, and a sevenfold transformation
今宵も集え インターネット
Gather again tonight, Internet
推し事に幸あれ
Blessings upon your fan activities
此処はまるで桃源郷
This place is just like a utopia
いっせーので よいよいよいよいっ
One, two, and... yoi yoi yoi yoi
浮世に隠れツノ光る
Hidden in the transient world, horns shining
どっちでも よいよいよいよいっ
Either way is fine, yoi yoi yoi yoi
我が道を行け
Go your own way
ゆらゆらり 恋い焦がれ
Swaying, swaying, longing for love
刹那に燃ゆる この想いは
These feelings burning in a moment
まだ分からないけど
I don't know yet, but...
実らせて
Let them bear fruit
咲き乱れよ
Bloom in profusion
御人も獣も通りゃんせ
Humans and beasts alike, please pass through
狛犬狐も跳び回れ
Guardian dogs and foxes, run around too
命は短し
Life is short
我武者羅に刻め
Carve it in recklessly
一富士二鷹で百は鬼
First Fuji, second hawk, and a hundred are oni
千客万来 おいでませ
A flood of customers, welcome
天晴れお祭りじゃ
Splendid festival it is
打ちまくれ
Beat them away
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and make merry, the banquet continues
舞え おにけもだんす
Dance, the Onikemo Dance
ヤヤヤヤヤ
Ya ya ya ya ya
コンコンコンコンッ
Kon kon kon kon
みょんみょんみょんみょんっ
Myaon myaon myaon myaon
さあさあ お手を拝借
Now then, your hands please
鬼火飛ばして いたずらしたい
Want to fly will-o'-the-wisps and play pranks
人間様と駄洒落遊び (あらよっと！)
Puns with humans (oh, more!)
親に薬と中指付けて
Medicine for parents and a middle finger...
好こるは激辛稲荷寿司 (コンッ)
Your fans like super spicy inarizushi (kon!)
犬も歩けば占い当たる
Even if a dog walks, they'll hit the fortune
出でよ召喚ハトタウルス (うわぁっビックリしたぁ！)
Come forth, summon Hatotaurus (Whoa, I was surprised!)
スーパーチャットもよいよいっ
Super Chat too, yoi yoi
小判を投げて圧かける
Throw coins and apply pressure
めんこい阿呆でてえな
A cute fool has appeared
甘き夢見し
Saw a sweet dream
ふわふわり 優しい風
Softly, softly, a gentle breeze
華麗に花が散るように
Like flowers falling elegantly
少し切ないけど
A little bit painful, but...
見届けて
Watch over it
咲き誇るわ
Blooming in full glory
物怪(もののけ)偶像(アイドル)神仏
Spirit idols, gods and buddhas
仮想(バーチャル)現世(リアル)も垣根無し
Virtual and real, no boundaries
尻尾を振り回し
Wagging tails around
天下掴もうぜ
Let's seize the world
心象風景 生放送
Mental scenery, live broadcast
策は無くとも奇策は有り
Even without a plan, there's a surprise move
魂を込めて
Put your soul into it
打ちまくれ
Beat them away
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and make merry, the banquet continues
舞え おにけもだんす
Dance, the Onikemo Dance
言いたいことがあるんだ余！
I have something to say!
やっぱりケモミミ可愛いよ！
As I thought, animal ears are cute!
好き好き大好きやっぱ好き！
Love, love, really love you, I really do!
やっと見つけたお嬢さま！
Finally found my lady!
過去と未来を繋いでいく
Connecting the past and the future
夢を追いかけどこまでも！
Chasing dreams anywhere!
世界で一番、愛してる！
I love you more than anything in the world!
アイ・シ・テ・ル！
I-L-O-V-E-Y-O-U!
しゃなりしゃなり 凸(とつ)いでいく
Gracefully going to the groom's house
狐の嫁入りの後には
After the fox's wedding...
虹が出ているから
Because a rainbow is out...
紡がせて
Let it be woven
咲き続けましょう
Let's continue to bloom
踊りましょう
Let's dance
御人も獣も通りゃんせ
Humans and beasts alike, please pass through
狛犬狐も跳び回れ
Guardian dogs and foxes, run around too
命は短し
Life is short
我武者羅に刻め
Carve it in recklessly
一富士二鷹で百は鬼
First Fuji, second hawk, and a hundred are oni
千客万来 おいでませ
A flood of customers, welcome
天晴れお祭りじゃ
Splendid festival it is
打ちまくれ
Beat them away
歌え騒げ 宴は続く
Sing and make merry, the banquet continues
舞え おにけもだんす
Dance, the Onikemo Dance
ヤヤヤヤヤ
Ya ya ya ya ya
コンコンコンコンッ
Kon kon kon kon
みょんみょんみょんみょんっ
Myaon myaon myaon myaon
鬼狐犬 神社～！
Oni Fox Dog Shrine!
わーー！はい、はい、はい、はい！
Waaa! Yes, yes, yes, yes!
一曲目からちょっと激しい曲やっちゃいましたね。
We just did a bit of a high-energy song right from the start.
やっちゃいましたね。
We did.
やっちゃいましたね、ドキドキしておりますけれども。
We did, I'm nervous but excited.
皆さん見てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you for watching!
ありがとーー！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you very much!
ってことで改めてね、自己紹介をしていきましょー！
So, once again, let's do our self-introductions!
いぇーい！フーフー！
Yeeey! Hoo hoo!
はい！いろはにほへと あやふぶみ、フブ担当なのかな？白上フブキです！
Hi! Irohanihoheto AyaFubuMi's Fubu-representative, I guess? I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
いぇーい！フブ担当だよ！
Yeeey! You're the Fubu-representative!
フブフブフブ！そしてそしてそして！
Fubu fubu fubu! And, and, and!
はい！あやふぶみのあや担当の百鬼あやめです！
Hi! I'm AyaFubuMi's Aya-representative, Nakiri Ayame!
よよよよ～！
Yo yo yo yo!
おはー！
Oha!
おはよーみの、みたとの、大神ミオでーす！
Good morning everyone! It's Ookami Mio!
おはどこへやってしまったのか...
Where did the "Oha" go?
いなくなった、いなくなりました。
It's gone, it disappeared.
ってことでね、1曲目はね、皆さん大好き、鬼灯ダンス、踊らせていただきましたけども。
So, the first song was "Onikemo Dance," which everyone loves.
鬼灯ダンスー！
Onikemo Dance!
いや、疲れたね。
Wow, that was tiring.
しんどいです。
I'm exhausted.
あやふびみの中でこれがマックス...これが限界マックスの曲だぞ！
This is the max for AyaFubiMio... this song is our absolute limit!
いや、この後も曲が控えてるということでね。
Well, we have more songs coming up.
恐ろしいですよ、恐ろしいですよ、はい。
That's scary, that's scary.
ちなみにさっきのおにけも間違えた人ー？
By the way, who messed up the Onikemo Dance just now?
はーい！
Me!
みんな、細かいところちょくちょく間違えました。
Everyone, we all messed up small parts here and there.
ちょいちょいね、間違えてると思いますけどもね。
A little bit here and there, I think we made mistakes.
いや、足とかこれね、むちゃくちゃだったけど。
Yeah, the legwork was a mess.
ワンチャン、カメラで見えてない可能性もある。
There's a chance the camera didn't catch it.
カットされてるかもしれないのでね。
It might have been cut out.
見ないふりしてください、お願いします！
Please pretend you didn't see anything!
ね、でもしかしこうやってね、おにけもね、ホロライブの公式放送で踊ったっけ？
But anyway, have we ever danced Onikemo on an official Hololive broadcast?
踊ったことはない、初めて。踊ったことはないよね？初めてだよね？
We haven't. It's the first time. Right? First time?
初めてだったよね、初お披露目みたいな。
It was the first time, like a debut performance.
MVではね、踊ってましたけどもね。
We did dance in the MV, though.
ね、皆様これTikTokとかにも上がってて、いろいろな方が踊ってくださいましたけど。
It's on TikTok too, and many people have danced to it.
皆様、ちゃんと踊ってくれました？これ、テュッテュッテュッテュッ...
Did you all dance to it properly? This part...
カラオケとかでガチ恋口上とかね。
Like doing the Gachikoi call at karaoke.
ね、皆様ちゃんと言ってくれましたか？言えるかな？
Did everyone do the call? Can you say it?
やっぱりおにけもみみ可愛いよー！うー！そーれー！はーっ！
As expected, Onikemo ears are cute! Woo! There! Ha!
よー！よー！よー！よー！よー！よー！
Yo! Yo! Yo!
あれ？あれ？あれ？ラップみたいになってますけど。
Wait, it's turning into a rap.
そうやね。でもこの曲やっぱり勢いがあっていいね。
That's true. But this song has great energy.
またなんかおにけもダンスみたいな曲も3人で踊れたらいいな、チラッ、チラッ。
I hope the three of us can dance to a song like Onikemo Dance again. *Glance, glance*
チラッ、チラッ。
*Glance, glance*
まあ、もうちょっと速さ的には、もうちょっと落としてもいい。あ、逆？
Well, maybe a bit slower... oh, the other way?
わかんない、もっと速くなってくるかも、今度は。
I don't know, it might get even faster next time.
さらに上がってく？さらにもしすると...さらに上を行く？
Even faster? Maybe... even higher?
痙攣しちゃうよ、もう！ダンスやってたら、もしかするとね、ちょっと痙攣しながらやることになるかも。
I'll have a seizure! If we keep dancing like that, I might end up doing it while twitching!
それはまずい、それはまずい。
That's not good, that's not good.
はい、もうちょっとBPM落とした感じの曲とかね、歌いたいね。
Yeah, I'd like to sing a song with a lower BPM.
ゆったりで、ゆったりでお願いします。
Slowly, please. Keep it slow.
そしてそして、次の曲は、お、何を歌うんですか、ミオさん？
And now, for the next song... Oh, what are we singing, Mio-san?
あ、あ、あ、次の曲いっちゃいますか？いいですか？
Ah, ah, ah, should we move to the next song? Is it okay?
ま、実はね、我々発表させていただいた曲で、まだダンスをお披露目してない曲ありますよ。
Actually, there's a song we've released but haven't performed the dance for yet.
曲はみんな聞いたことあると思いますけども。
I think everyone has heard the song.
その曲をやっちゃおうかなって。
I'm thinking of doing that song.
え！いいんですか？やっちゃいますか？
Eh! Is it okay? Are we doing it?
そんなに動いて大丈夫ですか？この後のダンス、体力やばい...
Is it okay to move that much? The dance after this... my stamina is low.
はい、ちょっとね、準備しましょうかね。
Right, let's get ready.
この状態で言うの？それでは聴いてください、って。
Saying it in this pose? "Now, please listen"?
それでは聴いてください、鬼灯日和！
Now, please listen: Hozuki Biyori!
鬼灯日和
作詞・作曲・編曲：おぐらあすか (Hifumi,inc.)
Hozuki Biyori
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Asuka Ogura (Hifumi,inc.)
沈む朱音日 染まる坂道
The setting crimson sun dyes the slope
伝う雫に 嬉しさ滲む
Tears flow down, blurring with joy
夜の帳の 近付く音に はしゃいだ君の声一つ
In the sound of approaching night's veil, a single voice of yours in high spirits
空に響いた
Resonated in the sky
稲荷の前で待ち合わせ 連なる鳥居潜り抜け
Meeting in front of the Inari shrine, passing through the row of torii gates
鬼灯の甘い風 胸をすり抜けていく
The sweet wind of ground cherries slips through my chest
踊ろうよ
Let's dance
廻れ 廻れ 手を叩いてほら
Spin, spin, clap your hands, look
見様見真似で輪になって
Form a circle, following what you see
ぎこちない振付に舞う 袂はひらひら
Dancing with awkward steps, sleeves fluttering
踊れ 踊れ 手をとりあって
Dance, dance, taking each other's hands
上気した頬 牡丹色
Flushed cheeks, the color of peonies
鳴り響く 太鼓の音に
To the resounding beat of the drums
紅く、飛沫弾けた
Red, droplets burst forth
キミに気づかれたかな？
I wonder if you noticed me?
響くざわめき
Resonant murmurs,
燃ゆる篝火
a burning bonfire.
揺らぐ気持ちに
Let your feelings
想い乗せよう
ride on your wavering heart.
祭り囃子が
The festival music
遠く浮世に
in the distant floating world.
天狐の星の雲隠れ
The heavenly fox's star hidden by clouds,
胸を突いた
pierced my chest.
今宵 空には朧月
Tonight, a hazy moon in the sky,
霞んだ心 誤魔化した
deceiving a clouded heart.
玉響に揺らめいて
Wavering for a moment,
胸をすり抜けたら
if it slips through my chest,
目を閉じて
close your eyes.
眠れ眠れ 意識は透明
Sleep, sleep, consciousness is transparent,
一夜一夜に募る様
growing night after night.
月明り照らす花びら
Petals illuminated by moonlight,
散るははらはら
falling fluttering.
泣いて泣いて 流るるは雫
Crying, crying, flowing are droplets,
嫁入り前の小夜時雨
a evening shower before a wedding.
傘の外 狐日和に
Outside the umbrella, in the fox's weather,
袖のしぐれ 隠した
hid the drizzle on the sleeve.
キミに気づかれない様に
So that you won't notice.
天つ風 雲の通い路
Winds of heaven, the path of the clouds,
閉ざし見ゆる 夢のまにまに
at the mercy of the dreams seen while closed.
幾星霜 想い焦がれた
Longing for many years,
このひと時が 絶えません様に...
may this moment never end...
ぽつり願う
A lonely wish.
止まれ止まれ 時間よ止まれ
Stop, stop, time stop,
夢の心地をご笑味あれ
enjoy the feeling of a dream.
狐火の狼煙に乗せた
Riding on the signal fire of foxfire,
心ゆらゆら
heart wavering.
踊れ踊れ 手を取り合って
Dance, dance, holding hands,
軽快な歩調 水鏡
a light pace on the water mirror.
幸せの百鬼夜行に
In the happy night parade of a hundred demons,
連なる思い出たち
memories lined up.
今宵 キミに幸あれ
May you be happy tonight.
うわー！
Whoa!
やりきりましたー！
We did it!
皆さん、どうでしたかー？
How was it, everyone?
いや、そんな、ね、初ダンスお披露目！
I mean, you know, our first dance performance!
初ダンスお披露目でしたね！
It was our first dance reveal!
もう、ほんと、ドナドナしちゃって！
We were really just so nervous!
わっしょいわっしょいしましたけども。
We were all hyped up.
いや、でも楽しいですね、この曲ね、ダンス。
But it's fun, dancing to this song.
ねー、楽しかったねー！
Yeah, it was fun!
なんですけどもー！
But wait, there's more!
なんと、なんと！もう一曲...
Guess what, guess what! One more song...
今日はあるんですよね？
We have one today, right?
そんな、3曲あるとは聞いてないです。
I haven't heard about having three songs.
そうですね、もう一曲あります！
That's right, we have one more song!
はい。それでは、何かと言いますと...
Yes. Now, as for what it is...
え、言っちゃうんですか？
Wait, are you going to say it?
言ったほうがいいですか？言っていいんですか？
Should I? Is it okay to say it?
言っちゃうんですか？我々が残されてる曲...
Are you going to say it? The song we have left...
まあ、『百花繚乱花吹雪』ではないです！
Well, it's not 'Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki'!
なんと、この後、24時から配信が開始されます！
Actually, it will be released at 24:00 tonight!
我々いろはにほへと あやふぶみ、新曲！
From us, Irohanihoheto Ayafubumi, a new song!
『恋情詩歌』！！
'Renjou Shika'!!
『恋情詩歌』お披露目ー！イエーイ！
'Renjou Shika' reveal! Yay!
恋情詩歌！恋情詩歌！そんな曲じゃないから！
Renjou Shika! Renjou Shika! It's not that kind of song!
どんな曲なのかな？ねー、どうだろうね。
I wonder what it's like? Yeah, I wonder.
ねー。今回、初お披露目ということで。
Yeah. Since it's the first reveal today.
ちょっとね、今までとは違った楽曲と...
It's a song that's a bit different from before...
なっておりますよね。
It's become that way, hasn't it?
どんな曲なのかな。
I wonder what kind of song it is.
ねえ、どんな、どんな、どんな曲なんでしょうねえ。
Yeah, I wonder what kind of song it'll be.
知ってるやろがい！このあとやるんだぞ！
You know it already! We're performing it right after this!
かわいい感じかな？
Is it a cute kind of song?
かわいい感じかな。やっぱね。
Maybe it's a cute feel. Right?
どんな感じかな。
I wonder how it'll feel.
和風な感じ？和風。
A Japanese style? Japanese.
和風でかわいい感じかな。どうかな？
A Japanese and cute feel? I wonder?
やりますかじゃあ。
Shall we do it then?
聴いてみてからのお楽しみ。お楽しみ。
Something to look forward to after you hear it.
お楽しみ。
Look forward to it.
ではではではでは、最初位置覚えてますか？
Now then, do you remember your starting positions?
どうだったっけね。
How was it again?
やばいやばい。やばいやばい。
Oh no, oh no. Oh no, oh no.
そうだ、こんな感じだったっけな。
Right, I think it was something like this.
そうです。ここですよ。ここですよもう。
Yes. It's here. Right here.
忘れないで、歌詞も大丈夫かい？覚えてるかい？ちゃんと。
Don't forget, are you okay with the lyrics too? Do you remember them?
えっと、恋、情、詩、歌、入ってる。こんな感じだった。
Umm, Renjou Shika... it's in there. It was like this.
うわー、ちょっと二人ともちょっと不安になってきましたなあ。
Whoa, I'm starting to get a bit worried about you two.
まあでも行きましょうかね、じゃあね。
Well, but let's go for it anyway.
はい。
Okay.
じゃあみんなで行きますよ、タイトル。それでは聴いてください。
Let's all announce the title together. Now then, please listen.
せーの。恋情詩歌！
Ready? Renjou Shika!
恋情詩歌
作詞：藤村鼓乃美 (Hifumi,inc.)
作曲・編曲：板倉孝徳 (Hifumi,inc.)
Renjou Shika
Lyrics: Konomi Fujimura (Hifumi,inc.)
Composition/Arrangement: Takanori Itakura (Hifumi,inc.)
言えぬ言葉の数を数えてみては
Counting the number of unspoken words
(一、二、三、四、五、六、七、八と)
(One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight)
小さなこの両手じゃ数えきれない
These small hands cannot count them all
愛の唄が今も生まれて
A song of love is being born even now
頭隠していても
Even if I hide my head
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
I can't hide my horns or tail, I can't stop it
覗いては雲がくれ 乙女の恋情詩歌
Peeking then hiding in the clouds, a maiden's love poem
気づかずに気がついてよ
Notice me without even realizing it
秘め心は五月の闇
The hidden heart is the darkness of May
その向こうで舞い踊る
Dancing beyond that
恋慕う君へと届くように
Hoping it reaches you, whom I love
みんな盛り上がってる！？最後までちゃんとついてくるんだよ！いくぞー！
Everyone, are you hyped!? Follow us until the end! Let's go!
側で聞こえてしまう程鳴り響く
It echoes so much it can be heard nearby
(ドキドキッドキッドキッドキドキッドキッ)
(Thump-thump, thump-thump...)
心塞いでも増すばかりで
Even if I close my heart, it only increases
クラクラする程の感情
An emotion so strong it makes me dizzy
目線逸らしてみても
Even if I turn my gaze away
角も尻尾も隠せない止められない
I can't hide my horns or tail, I can't stop it
夢見ては雲超えて 乙女の恋情詩歌
Dreaming and crossing clouds, a maiden's love poem
愛さずに愛しててよ
Love me without even loving me
恋心は五月の闇
The heart of love is the darkness of May
その向こうに何を見る
What do you see beyond that?
恋慕う君へと届くように
Hoping it reaches you, whom I love
真心の鬼火そっと灯す
Gently lighting the soul-fire of sincerity
アイラブユウの数光らせば
If I let the number of 'I love you's shine
化かしてあげましょうほら夢中
I'll bewitch you, look, you're entranced
捧げるものなら辛口で
If it's something to offer, let it be dry
高く声あげりゃあ集まれ
If we raise our voices high, gather round
どこに居たって遠く響かせ
No matter where you are, let it echo far
物の怪乙女の三人衆
The trio of monster maidens
そこのけそこのけ我らが通る
Out of the way, we're coming through
願えばいつかは晴れよと
Hoping that one day it will clear up
闇に隠せし恋心
A heart of love hidden in the darkness
雲の切れ間に明かり射す
Light shines through the break in the clouds
今この時に
In this moment right now
見つめれば隠してはおけない恋情詩歌
Staring at it, I can't hide it, this love poem
触れないで抱き寄せてよ
Don't touch me, just pull me close
素直になれたら五月の闇
If I could be honest, the darkness of May
君だけに唄を歌おう
I'll sing a song just for you
恋した浮き雲へ と伝うように
As if conveying it to the floating clouds I've loved
愛した浮き雲へと 届くように
As if reaching the floating clouds I've cherished
はじまー！はじまー！はじまー！
It's starting! It's starting! It's starting!
宿題が全然終わらない全国のヤバめな諸君！
To all the students nationwide who haven't finished their homework!
急がなきゃ 寝なきゃいいじゃない！
If you need to hurry, just don't sleep!
頑張れ 頑張れ 私！
Do your best, do your best, me!
バーリラ 脳内フロア
Barira, inside my brain floor
暴れてる カルナバル
A raging carnival
アドレナリン ドパドパ
Adrenaline's gushing
究極の PANIGHT
The ultimate PANIGHT
パリナイ パリナイ パラパパパリナイ パリナイ パリナイ 終わる気しない (終わる気しない)
PANIGHT PANIGHT Parapapa PANIGHT, PANIGHT PANIGHT, feels like it won't end (won't end)
We Are NEGI☆U! We Are NEGI☆U! We Are NEGI☆U! Let's Go!
スゴい ヤバい パない 物足りない
Incredible, crazy, insane, not enough
ないない尽くしでとめどない (とめどない)
Nothing but nothingness, endless (endless)
スゴい ヤバい パない Saturday Night
Incredible, crazy, insane, Saturday Night
とにかくもうやるしかない (やるしかない)
Anyway, there's no choice but to do it (do it)
スゴい ヤバい パない 物足りない
Incredible, crazy, insane, not enough
全力モ/モ/モ/申したい (もしだい)
Full power, I/I/I want to say (want to say)
たった一度の青春は (わ～！？)
This youth that only happens once (Wha~?!)
毎日エンジョイ PANIGHT
Enjoy PANIGHT every day
あーお集まりの旦那様、えーそうじゃない様、ご唱和ください
Ah, gentlemen gathered here, and those who aren't, please join in
それゆけ Say Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa
Let's go, Say Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa Whoa
Come on DJ!
Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa Pa... PANIGHT!
うえ～～～～～～ん
Waaaaaaaaaah
Everybody Sing Along ブチ上げ Sing Along
Everybody Sing Along, get hyped Sing Along
陽キャでも陰キャでも勉強だ ワッショイ ワッショイ
Extrovert or introvert, it's study time, Heave-ho!
太陽は理科系？
Is the sun a science major?
おしゃべり ノンノンノンスノンノンノン
Chatting is non-non-non-s-non-non-non
遊んじゃダメダメ (ダメダメ)
No playing allowed (No-no)
ごめんなさーい (ごめんなさーい)
I'm sorry! (I'm sorry!)
朝が来て 眠れない どうしよう...
Morning comes and I can't sleep, what should I do...
神様も 両手挙げて Fly High
Even God is putting His hands up, Fly High
なんとかするしかない
I've gotta do something about it
頑張れ 出来るって
Do your best, you can do it
ド派手にかましちゃるね (バキバキ)
Let's do it flashily (Crackling)
Put Your Hands Up! Put Your Hands Up!
パリナイ パリナイ パラパパパリナイ
PANIGHT PANIGHT Parapapa PANIGHT
パリナイ パリナイ 時間がない (時間がない)
PANIGHT PANIGHT, there's no time (no time)
We Are NEGI☆U! We Are NEGI☆U! We Are NEGI☆U! Let's Go!
あ、えーと、レッツゴー！w
Ah, um, let's go! lol
スゴい ヤバい パない 物足りない
Incredible, crazy, insane, not enough
板のバッター かたじけない (かたじけない)
Sorry, butter on the board (my bad)
スゴい ヤバい パない Sunday Night
Incredible, crazy, insane, Sunday Night
とにかくもう やるしかない (やるしかない)
Anyway, there's no choice but to do it (do it)
スゴい ヤバい パない 物足りない
Incredible, crazy, insane, not enough
宿題やっぱり 終わらない (終わらない)
The homework after all isn't finishing (isn't finishing)
たった一度の青春は (わ～！？)
This youth that only happens once (Wha~?!)
満開HAPPY PANIGHT (一緒にせーの！)
Full bloom HAPPY PANIGHT (All together now!)
ねね～、あてぃ～、終わんねーよこれ～
Nene~, Ati~, I'm never gonna finish this~
スバル先輩～～！この問題全然わかんないんですけどー！
Subaru-senpai~! I don't get this problem at all!
えーっ！何その鉛筆！めっちゃ可愛いじゃん、いいなー！
Wha-! What's with that pencil! It's super cute, I'm jealous!
でしょう～～ww キラキラ光るんですよ～ホホホ
Right? lol It sparkles and shines! Hohoho
え、へへ、みんな、元気だなあ...
E-hehe, everyone's so energetic...
よ、陽キャって、こんな時も、すごいなー...
W-wow, extroverts are amazing even at times like this...
ははははは......えーと......ははは......
Hahahahaha... um... hahah...
は、はーりー！w
P-PANIGHT! lol
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ということでー、ホロライブ2期生、大空スバル！そして！
And so, hololive 2nd generation, Oozora Subaru! And!
皆様どうもこんあくあー！湊あくあでーす！そして！
Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua! Minato Aqua here! And!
こんねねー！桃鈴ねねねねねねです！よろしくにぇー！
Kon-Nene! I'm Momosuzu Nenenenenene! Nice to meet ya!
私たち！せーの！NEGI☆Uでーす！
We are! Ready, set! NEGI☆U!
あー、ギリギリですねーw
Ah, that was close! lol
マジ、でもこの向き、こっちの方が、え？
Seriously, but this way, it's better... eh?
こう？こう？どっちかにして、どっちかにしてー
Like this? Like this? Pick one, just pick one!
いや無理だろこれ、なんで決めずにやったんだよこれ
No, that's impossible. Why did we do this without deciding first?
今突然だったんだから、しょうがないじゃない
It was so sudden just now, so we couldn't help it.
まあでもね、ギリギリ決まっててということで
Well anyway, since we barely managed it...
さあ、1曲目はね、NEGI☆Uの新曲、PANIGHT披露させていただきました！
Now, for our first song, we performed NEGI☆U's new song, PANIGHT!
PANIGHT、みんなどうだったー？
How did everyone like PANIGHT?
まあでもみんなね、TikTokで多分ショートバージョン聞いてくれてると思うから
Well, I think most people have heard the short version on TikTok.
フルでね、MVもね、出てるしね
The full version and the MV are out too.
ねー、ねー、どうだった、どうだったー？
Right? Right? How was it? How was it?
やっぱ陽キャソングだよねー
It's definitely an extrovert song!
なんかさ、すごいキラキラしてなかった？
Didn't it feel super sparkly?
結構圧強かったよねw
The pressure was quite strong, wasn't it? lol
あつも強かったし、
Atsu was also strong,
最後のあつのパパパ「パパリー」みたいな。
like Atsu's 'Pa-pa-parii' at the end.
パパリー！
Pa-parii!
いや、乗り切れてないよね？
Wait, you weren't really feeling it, were you?
え、乗り切れてないの？
Eh, I wasn't?
みんなもどちらかと言うとパパリーのタイプだよね？
Everyone is more of the 'Pa-parii' type, right?
いやいや、ねねち、ねねちの根っこに聞いてみてよ。
No no, Nene-chi, ask your own roots.
みんなどうだった？あつ先輩もバッチリだった？
How was it, everyone? Was Atsu-senpai perfect too?
うんうん、あつしバッチリ。
Yeah, yeah, Atsu-shi's perfect.
大丈夫みたい。
She seems fine.
プニプニ (Puni Puni)
Puni Puni (Puni Puni)
ほっぺたプニプニ (Puni Puni)
Hoppeta Puni Puni (Puni Puni)
どやっとラッキーラッキー (Lucky lucky)
Doyatto Lucky Lucky (Lucky lucky)
ドレミファニファニ (Funny funny)
Do-Re-Mi Funny Funny (Funny funny)
それはハッピーイェーーーーー！！
So re wa Happy Yeahhhhh!!!
さあ、NEGI☆U最後の曲です！
Now, it's NEGI☆U's last song!
今日は見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to see us today!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ありがとう！
よし、じゃあポジションについて。
Alright, let's get into position.
はーい。
Okay.
どこだっけ？ここか。
Where was it? Is it here?
はい！それでは聴いてください！
Alright! Please listen to...
『よくばりキュートガール』！
“Yokubari Cute Girl”!
よくばりキュートガール
作詞：まろん (IOSYS)　作曲・編曲：田中とわ (Hifumi, inc.)
Yokubari Cute Girl
Lyrics: Maron (IOSYS) Composition/Arrangement: Towa Tanaka (Hifumi, inc.)
ゴーレッゴー！時間だ！
Go let's go! It's time!
待ち合わせはいつものカフェで
Let's meet at the usual cafe
Chu-Chu-Wa Chu-wa-Chu-wa-Chu-Chu
走れ！ダウンタウン　ショートカットだ
Run! Downtown! Take a shortcut and
RUN RUN　駆け抜けよう
RUN RUN, let's dash through
Chu-Chu-Wa Chu-wa-Chu-wa-Chu-Chu
たまには　髪型をふわり
Once in a while, style your hair soft and fluffy
オシャレモードで　歩こうよ
Let's walk in fashion mode
スクランブルで　転けちゃって
Tripping at the scramble crossing
注目浴びて　ゴメンって
Getting all the attention and saying sorry
笑ってよ！（もう！）
Laugh it off! (Geez!)
すぐ怒らないで
Don't get mad right away
楽しい！（楽しい！）美味しい！（美味しい！）
It's fun! (Fun!) It's tasty! (Tasty!)
なんでもシェアハピ（ハッピー！）
Let's share the happiness for everything (Happy!)
キミと（キミと）キミと（キミと）
With you (with you) with you (with you)
夢みたい　お年頃（お年頃♪）
A dream-like age (the prime of youth♪)
ワクワクしちゃお　ドキドキしちゃお
Let's get excited, let's get our hearts racing
スチャラカモードで（イェイイェイ！）
In a carefree mode (Yay yay!)
よくばりなんです
I'm just greedy
あざとくパシャリ　キュートなエブリデイ
Take a calculatingly cute pic, cute everyday
出たわね！おニューのアイス
There it is! The new ice cream
行こうよ！Hurry！Hurry！
Let's go! Hurry! Hurry!
どれどれ？迷っちゃう
Let's see? I can't decide
やっぱりいつものパンケーキ
I'll go with the usual pancake after all
見つけた　シアワセのカケラ
Found a piece of happiness
ガラスボトル　詰め込むの
Stuffing it into a glass bottle
青空テラス　キラキラ
Blue sky terrace, sparkling
楽しみたいの　まだまだ
I want to enjoy myself more and more
見えるかな？素敵なレインボースカイ
Can you see it? A wonderful rainbow sky
「さあ～今日もたくさん買い物するぞ～」
"Alright~ I'm gonna do a lot of shopping today too~"
「へへ、待ってくださいよ～スバル先輩～」
"Hehe, wait for me~ Subaru-senpai~"
「あれ、この服、可愛い…」
"Oh, this outfit is cute..."
「お邪魔しますよー！」
"Pardon us!"
「お客さん、お目が高いですね～！」
"Customer, you have good taste!"
「似合ってるじゃん！絶対これ買ったほうがいいですよ！」
"It looks good on you! You should definitely buy this!"
「えっ、そうかなぁ、えへ、えへへ～」
"Eh, do you think so? Ehe, ehehe~"
いつも　いつも　ありがとう
Always, always, thank you
浮かぶ　笑顔　シャッターチャンスだ！（はぁ！）
Smiling faces appearing, it's a photo opportunity! (Hah!)
楽しい！（楽しい！）美味しい！（美味しい！）
It's fun! (Fun!) It's tasty! (Tasty!)
なんでもシェアハピ（ハッピー！）
Let's share the happiness for everything (Happy!)
キミと（キミと）キミと（キミと）
With you (with you) with you (with you)
夢みたい　お年頃（お年頃♪）
A dream-like age (the prime of youth♪)
ワクワクしちゃお　ドキドキしちゃお
Let's get excited, let's get our hearts racing
スチャラカモードで（イェイイェイ！）
In a carefree mode (Yay yay!)
よくばりなんです
I'm just greedy
「バナナはお菓子に入りますか～！？」
"Do bananas count as snacks!?"
あれも（あれも！）それも（それも！）
That one too! (That one too!) That one as well! (That one as well!)
全部全部欲しいの (もう一回！)
I want all of them, everything (One more time!)
キミと（キミと）キミと（キミと）
With you (with you) with you (with you)
作るのだ　パラダイス (パラダイス☆)
Let's create a paradise (Paradise☆)
おにぎり食べて　お菓子も食べて
Eat rice balls, eat snacks too
シアワセ笑っちゃお（イェイイェイ！）
Let's laugh with happiness (Yay yay!)
家族みたいだね
We're like a family, aren't we
あざとくパシャリ　キュートなエブリデイ
Take a calculatingly cute pic, cute everyday
NEGI☆U
ねぎゆーのぱにゃーだ
2022.06.01 NOW ON SALE
NEGI☆U
Negi-yuu no pa-nya-da
2022.06.01 NOW ON SALE
恋情詩歌 (RENJO SHIIKA)
いろはにほへっと あやふぶみ
2022年6月6日0時 デジタル配信解禁！
RENJO SHIIKA
Irohanihohetto Ayafubumi
June 6, 2022, 0:00 AM Digital release available!
hololive IDOL PROJECT ユニット初集合 Live
hololive IDOL PROJECT Unit First Gathering Live